raileasy.co.uk 2019-12-10

# Privacy

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally Identifiable Information' (PII) is being used online. PII is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. It has been compiled so as to comply with current UK, US and EU legislation, so far as we are aware. If you have any question regarding the confidentiality policy, please contact us at: management@raileasy.co.uk

Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

*Ferries Trains Plans Limted T/A Raileasy are registered with the Information Commissioner's Office - https://ico.org.uk/ESDWebPages/Entry/ZA308213

 **Who controls your personal data?**

  * Ferries Trains Planes Ltd is a company registered in the UK: Company Number 3067728
  * Address: 10 Station Parade, High Street, Wanstead, London, E11 1QF
  * Ferries Trains Planes Ltd data protection representative is their Customer Service and Marketing Director
  * You can contact them at management@raileasy.co.uk
  * You can call them on 0208 989 3437
  * Ferries Trains Planes Ltd is registered as a Data Controller with the Information Commissioner’s Office Certificate Number ZA308213

 **1\. What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number or other details to help you with your experience.

We collect credit/debit card information as all transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are only stored in a masked format I.E with most of the digits removed.

 **2\. When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form or enter information on our site and provide us with feedback on our products or services

 **3\. Why we process your personal data and our legal justification for doing so:**

Our legal basis for the processing of personal data is our legitimate business interests, although we will also rely on contract, legal obligation and consent for specific uses of data.

 **4\. How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalise your experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested. (Produce train tickets)
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.
  * To quickly process your transactions.
  * To ask for ratings and reviews of services or products
  * To follow up with them after correspondence (live chat, email or phone inquiries)

 **5\. How do we protect your information?**

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order to maintain the safety of your personal information.

All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are only stored in a masked format I.E with most of the digits removed.

At any time you may review or update the personally identifiable information that we hold about you, by contacting us at the address below. To better safeguard your information, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections to your information.

 **6\. Do we use 'cookies'?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

 **7\. We use cookies to:**

Track visitor navigation. Cookies are small text files, stored on your machine used to track navigation and remember data and preferences submitted by the user. They do not contain personal or sensitive data or viruses and do not harm your computer

Raileasy operates an 'implied consent' policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy, you should either not use this site, delete the cookies having visited the site, or browse the site using your browser's anonymous usage setting (called "Incognito" in Chrome, "InPrivate" for Internet Explorer, "Private Browsing" in Firefox and Safari etc.) although this last option may affect your ability to purchase tickets from the site.  
The processing of the information and insight derived from the cookie placement is processed under the legal basis of ‘legitimate interest’.

 **8\. Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information.

 **9\. Third-party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

 **10\. Google**

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles.

https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

 **11\. We have implemented the following:**

  * Remarketing with Google AdSense
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

 **12\. Privacy Protection Act**

Is a law to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's requires any person or company that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared.

 **13\. We agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy' and can easily be found on the page specified above.

You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes:

  * On our Privacy Policy Page

Can change your personal information:  

  * By emailing us
  * By calling us

 **14\. Does our site allow third-party behavioural tracking?**

It's also important to note that we allow third-party behavioural tracking

 **15\. We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders.
  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred. (on the legal basis of soft opt-in criteria)

 **16\. We agree to the following:**  

  * Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Process opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

 **17\. If at any time you would like to Unsubscribe/Opt Out from receiving future emails:**

Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email by clicking the unsubscribe link

and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.

Or email us at admin@raileasy.co.uk or management@raileasy.co.uk

Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.

 **10 Station Parade  
Wanstead  
LONDON  
E11 1QF  
United Kingdom**

management@raileasy.co.uk

02089893437

#### Also in this section

### Top Savings Tips

  1. **1\. Book Early** \- [**Cheap train tickets**](http://raileasy.co.uk/home/cheap-train-tickets?utm_source=google&utm_medium=banner&utm_campaign=cheap_train_tickets_rms_page) are available up to 12 weeks in advance.
  2.  **2\. Avoid Travelling in Rush Hour** -[ **Off peak**](http://www.raileasy.co.uk/making-a-booking/fares-explained?utm_source=google&utm_medium=box&utm_campaign=fares_explained_landing%20_page%20_box) train tickets are cheaper!
  3.  **3\. Split Your Train Tickets** \- [**Split ticketing**](https://raileasy.trainsplit.com/main.aspx?utm_source=google&utm_medium=banner&utm_campaign=raileasy.trainsplit_re_landing%20pages), where the journey is broken down into smaller sections could save you a small fortune on the cost of train travel. Try it [**here**](https://raileasy.trainsplit.com/main.aspx?utm_source=google&utm_medium=banner&utm_campaign=raileasy.trainsplit_re_landing%20pages)
  4.  **4\. Cheapest fare Finder** -Our **[cheapest](http://www.raileasy.co.uk/home/cheapest-fare-finder?utm_source=google&utm_medium=box&utm_campaign=cheapers_fare_finder_landing%20_page_box) [fare finder](http://www.raileasy.co.uk/home/cheapest-fare-finder?utm_source=google&utm_medium=box&utm_campaign=cheapers_fare_finder_landing%20_page_box)** searches a wider time frame to locate cheaper rail tickets throughout the day.

### Find a Cheaper Fare

If you book with us then find a cheaper fare becomes available for the exact same journey on Raileasy we will refund the original **FREE OF CHARGE** when you re-book as part of our **BEST FARE GUARANTEE**
